梦是来自内心深处的信息
每当太阳低垂斜照沙漠之时 我的故乡
My planet, Arrakis, is so beautiful
when the sun is low.
厄拉科斯星球分外美丽
Rolling over the sands…
空气中漂浮着香料
You can see spice in the air.
夜幕降临 香料机车登陆
At nightfall, the spice harvesters land.
为避开白昼炽热 异星人争分夺秒采集
The outsiders race against time
to avoid the heat of the day.
我亲眼见证了他们怎样践踏我们的家园
They ravage our lands
in front of our eyes.
我知道了一切他们怎样蹂躏我们的同胞
Their cruelty to my people
is all I've known.
我出生很久以前 这些异星人 哈克南家族就来到这里
These outsiders, The Harkonnens,
came long before I was born.
通过控制香料生产 他们变得非常富有
By controlling the spice production
they became obscenely rich.
富可敌国
Richer than the Emperor himself.
我们的战士无法从哈克南人手中解放厄拉科斯
Our warriors couldn't free Arrakis
from the Harkonnens,
突然一天 皇帝下令 他们走了
but one day, by imperial decree,
they were gone.
为什么皇帝选择此道 谁是我们新的征服者
Why did the Emperor choose this path?
And who our next oppressors be?
10191年
厄崔迪家族的卡拉丹城堡
你早起真好
It's good you're up early.
父亲要你在帝国传令官抵达之前穿好正装
Father wants you in full dress
before the Emperor's herald arrives.
正装 军装吗
Full dress? Military?
礼服
Ceremonial.
已经决定之事 为何还要过场
Why do we have to go through all of this
when it's already been decided?
礼仪
Ceremony.
谢谢
Thank you.
如果你想要 就让我给你
If you want it make me give it to you.
- 用音言 - 妈妈 我刚睡醒
-Use the Voice.
-Mom, I just woke up.
- 把水给我 - 杯子听不见 你得命令我
-Give me the water.
-The glass can't hear you. Command me.
把水给我
Give me the water.
- 差一点 - 差一点
-Almost.
-Almost?
保罗 贝尼·杰瑟里特的技能需要苦学多年
Bene Gesserit skills
take years to learn, Paul.
你看来很累 又做梦了吗
You look tired. More dreams?
没有
No.
极端高温和恶劣气候
Extreme temperatures
and treacherous weather events
使厄拉科斯城外的生活无比艰难
make life outside the cities
of Arrakis truly hostile.
沙暴之力足以断金
With sandstorms powerful enough
to cut through the metal.
唯有被称为弗雷曼的土著部落能够适应并生存下来
Only the native tribes known as the Fremen
have adapted well enough to survive.
弗雷曼人宁愿居住在厄拉科斯最偏远的地区
Preferring to inhabit
the remotest regions of Arrakis
与被弗雷曼人称为夏胡鲁的巨大沙虫
the Fremen share the deep desert
with the giant sandworms
共享这片沙漠腹地
known to the Fremen as Shai-Hulud.
长期接触香料使部落有了他们独特的蓝眼睛
Long exposure to spice has given
the tribe their characteristic blue eyes,
“伊巴德之眼”
the eyes of Ibad.
弗雷曼人凶狠狡诈
Little else is known of the Fremen,
外界对他们所知甚少
except that they are dangerous
and unreliable.
弗雷曼人的袭击使得采集香料极其危险
Fremen attacks make spice harvesting
extremely hazardous.
对弗雷曼人而言 香料是神圣的迷幻剂
For the Fremen, spice
is the sacred hallucinogen
不仅维持生命 而且有益健康
which preserves life and brings
enormous health benefits.
对于帝国 宇航公会的领航员用这种香料
For the Imperium, the spice is used
by the navigators of the Spacing Guild
来寻找星际之间的安全通道
to find safe paths between the stars.
没有香料就没有星际航行
Without spice
interstellar travel is impossible,
这使它成为宇宙中最宝贵的物质
making it by far the most valuable
substance in the universe.
笑一笑 哥尼
Smile, Gurney.
我在笑
I am smiling.
他们远道而来办这个仪式要花多少钱
How much will it cost them traveling
all this way for this formality?
三名公会领航员 来回一共1,460,062索拉里斯
Three Guild navigators and a total
of 1,460,062 solaris for the round trip.
承蒙皇帝沙达姆·科里诺四世
By the grace of Shaddam IV
of the House Corrino,
登上已知宇宙帕迪沙皇帝的金狮宝座的恩典
Ascendant to the Golden Lion Throne
of Padishah Emperor of the Known Universe,
我作为星变使者前来宣旨
I stand before you
as Herald of the Change.
见证人有帝国宫廷成员
We are witnessed by members
of the Imperial Court,
宇航公会代表 和贝尼·杰瑟里特姐妹
representatives of the Spacing Guild,
and a sister of the Bene Gesserit.
皇上有旨
The Emperor has spoken:
“厄崔迪家族即刻接管厄拉科斯
"House Atreides shall immediately
take control of Arrakis
并永葆泰安”
and serve as its steward."
请接旨
Do you accept?
我们厄崔迪家族
We are the House Atreides.
永远忠诚 永不背叛
There is no call we do not answer.
There is no faith that we betray.
皇帝命令我们为厄拉科斯带去和平
The Emperor asks us
to bring peace to Arrakis.
厄崔迪家族接旨
House Atreides accepts.
厄崔迪
Atreides!
你的封印
Your seal.
这就 完成了
So, it's done?
完成了
It's done.
- 怎么样? - 稳定器太松了
-How was it?
-The stabilizers are too loose.
- 我来搞定 - 谢谢你 我的朋友
-I'll handle that.
-Thank you, my friend.
- 邓肯 - 好小子
-Duncan.
-My boy!
保罗 好小子
Paul, my boy.
那么 你明天和先遣队一起去厄拉科斯
So, you're going to Arrakis tomorrow
with the advance team?
是的 我明天和先遣队一起去厄拉科斯
Yes, I'm going to Arrakis tomorrow
with the advance team.
- 我想和你一起去 - 真的
-I'd like you to take me with you.
-You would?
那太糟糕了 因为不行
That's too bad, cause no.
邓肯
Duncan…
你想害我上军事法庭吗 怎么了
Are you trying to give me court-martial?
What's going on?
- 我能跟你说个秘密吗  - 当然 你懂的
-Can I trust you with something?
-Always. You know that.
我最近经常做梦
I've been having dreams.
梦到厄拉科斯星球和弗雷曼人
About Arrakis and the Fremen.
好吧 那又怎样
Okay, so?
我看见你了
I saw you.
和弗雷曼人一起
With the Fremen.
那么我真的找到他们了 你真棒 这是个好兆头 对吧
So I do find them? There you go.
That's a good omen right there, right?
兰维尔
Lanville!
我看见你倒下 战死沙场
I saw you lying dead. Fallen in battle.
如果我在 你不会死
I felt like if I had been there
you'd be alive.
首先 我不会死
First of, I'm not gonna die.
- 我是认真的 - 所以你才想跟我一起去
-You're not taking me seriously.
-That's why you wanna come with me?
听着 梦境虽美却是海市蜃楼
Listen, dreams make good stories,
若要美梦成真
but everything important
happens when we're awake,
你得从梦中醒来
because that's where
we make things happen.
- 看看你 长肌肉了吗 - 我有吗
-Look at you, put up some muscle?
-I did?
没有
No.
厄拉科斯见 好小子
See you in Arrakis, my boy.
父亲 我请求明天和邓肯·爱达荷
Father, I'd like to ask
to join Duncan Idaho
一起去厄拉科斯侦察
on a scout mission to Arrakis tomorrow.
我学过弗雷曼语 我可以胜任
I've studied the Fremen language.
I'd be an asset.
不可能
Out of the question.
你将和我们其他人一起 在几周后去厄拉科斯
You'll travel in a few weeks
to Arrakis like the rest of us.
我一直都在训练 不让去有何意义
I've been training my whole life…
What is the point if I'm not allowed--
你知道为什么 保罗 你是厄崔迪家族的未来
You know why, Paul.
You're the future of the House Atreides.
祖父还可以玩斗牛呢
And grandfather fought bulls for sport.
是的 看看他的下场
Yes, look where that got him.
我需要你在我身边 我们去到厄拉科斯将面对重重危险
I need you by my side. When we get
to Arrakis we'll face enormous danger.
什么危险 弗雷曼人 沙漠
What danger? The Fremen? The desert?
政治危机
Political danger.
望族都指望我们来领导 这威胁到了皇帝
The great houses look to us for leadership
and this threatens the Emperor.
他把厄拉科斯从哈克南家族手中夺走 交给我们
By taking Arrakis from the Harkonnens
and making it ours
是要挑起一场战争 让两大家族自相残杀
he sets the stage for a war
which would weaken both houses.
但如果我们坚定不移地汲取厄拉科斯的真正力量
But if we hold firm
and tap the true power of Arrakis
我们将空前强大
we could be stronger than ever.
这什么意思
What does that mean?
采集香料 继续奴役弗里曼人吗
Mining spice, keeping
the Fremen in their place?
我们不会比哈克南人好到哪里去
We'd be no better than Harkonnens.
不 通过和弗雷曼人结盟
No. By making an alliance with the Fremen.
这就是我派邓肯·爱达荷去做的
That's what I've sent
Duncan Idaho to arrange.
在这里 在卡拉丹 我们用空中力量和海上力量来统治
Here, on Caladan, we've ruled
by air power and sea power.
在厄拉科斯 我们必须借助沙漠的力量
On Arrakis, we need to cultivate
desert power.
我想让你加入我的委员会 了解我的工作
I want you sitting in
on my council, learn what I do.
如果我不是呢 爸爸
What if I'm not, dad?
不是什么
Not what?
厄崔迪家族的未来
The future of the House Atreides.
我也曾告诉我父亲我不想要这个
I told my father
I didn't want this either.
- 我想当飞行员 - 你从没告诉过我
-I wanted to be a pilot.
-You never told me that.
你爷爷说 “伟大之人 不求领导
Your grandfather said, "A great
man doesn't seek to lead.
时事造就 应运而生”
He's called to it. And he answers."
但如果你并不愿意
And if your answer is "no"
我也希望你知道
you'll still be the only thing
I ever needed you to be,
你依然是我的儿子
my son.
我找到了我的道路 我相信你也会找到
I found my own way to it.
Maybe you'll find yours.
为了列祖列宗
In their memory…
试试吧
give it a try.
不要背对门站着
Don't stand with your back to the door.
告诉你多少次
How many times do we have to tell you?
我从脚步声听出是你 哥尼·哈勒克
I could tell it was you
by your footsteps, Gurney Halleck.
有人可能模仿我的步伐
Someone might imitate my stride.
我分辨得出 你是新武器大师吗
I know the difference.
Are you the new weapons master?
邓肯·爱达荷不在了 我必须竭尽所能
With Duncan Idaho gone,
I must make do as best as I can.
选择你的刀
Choose your blade.
我今天过得不错 哥尼 给我们唱首歌吧
I've had quite a day, Gurney.
Give us a song instead.
鲁莽
That's rude.
快点 快点
Come on. Come on.
老家伙
Old man.
这么慢的速度能刺穿你的屏蔽场
The slow blade penetrates the shield.
- 我猜我今天没心情 - 心情 这跟心情有毛关系
-I'm guessing I'm not in the mood today.
-Mood? What's mood got to do with it?
不管心情如何 都必须战斗 现在 战斗
You fight when the necessity arises,
no matter the mood. Now, fight!
来吧
Come on!
- 你输了 - 是吗
-I have you.
-Aye.
往下看 大人 我们同归于尽
But look down, my lord.
You'd have joined me in death.
我看你“心情”很好啊
I see you found the mood.
- 未来有多糟  - 你还不明白 是吗
-Will it be that bad?
-You don't get it, do you?
你并不真正了解事态的严重性
You don't really understand the grave
nature of what's happening to us.
哈克南家族统治厄拉科斯八十年
For 80 years Arrakis belonged
to House Harkonnen.
拥有香料产地八十年 你能想象该有多富有吗
Eighty years of owning the spice fields.
Can you imagine the wealth?
在你的眼睛里  我没有看到我要的眼神
In your eyes, I need
to see it in your eyes.
你从没见过哈克南人 我见过
You never met Harkonners before. I have.
他们毫无人性 他们残酷无情
They are not human. They're brutal!
你必须做好准备
You have to be ready.
哈克南家族的杰迪主城堡
男爵大人
Lord Baron.
拉班
Rabban.
我们最后一艘飞船已经离开厄拉科斯 任务完成
The last of our ships
have left Arrakis. It's done.
很好
Very good.
叔叔 我们怎么会让这种事发生
Uncle, how did we let this happen?
皇帝怎么能把我们建造的一切
How can the Emperor
take everything we've built
拱手送给公爵 怎么能
and give it to that Duke? How?
别激动 这是爱
Don't be too sure, it's an act of love.
他什么意思
What does he mean?
祸兮福倚 福兮祸伏
When is a gift not a gift?
厄崔迪家族声势正在壮大
The Atreides Voice is rising
皇帝是个心胸狭小的人
and the Emperor is a jealous man.
一个危险且心胸狭小的人
A dangerous, jealous man.
保罗
Paul…
保罗 醒醒
Paul, wake up.
- 怎么了? - 穿好衣服跟我来
-What's wrong?
-Get dressed and come with me.
怎么了
What is this?
圣母盖尤斯·海伦·莫希亚姆来了
The Reverend Mother
Gaius Helen Mohiam is here.
她是我在贝尼·杰瑟里特学校的老师
She was my teacher
at the Bene Gesserit school.
她现在是皇帝的真言师
She's now Truthsayer
to the Emperor himself.
她想见见你
She would like to meet you.
为什么
Why?
她想知道你的梦
She wants to know about your dreams.
她怎么知道我的梦?
How does she know about my dreams?
- 为什么岳医生在这里? - 他只需要一点时间
-And why is Dr. Yueh here?
-He only needs a moment.
你好 少主
Hello, young master.
你妈妈让我为你检查一下
Your mother asked me to check your vitals.
怎么了
What's happening?
贝尼·杰瑟里特的事儿 我是略有所闻 她们说她们的存在是为了能造福更多的人
Bene Gesserit claims
to serve the greater good.
我并不想冒犯你的母亲 但说到底
But with all due respect to your mother,
她们做的一切都是为了她们自己人
they also serve their own agenda.
你什么意思
What are you saying?
当心点
Be careful.
他的心还是那么坚强 夫人
His heart is strong as ever, my lady.
别向任何人说
Not a word of this to anyone.
保罗
Paul…
记住你的训练
Remember your training.
你是谁
Who are you?
桀骜不驯的双眼 跟他父亲一样
Defiance in the eyes, like his father.
退下
Leave us.
你必须按圣母海伦·莫希亚姆说的一切去做
You must do everything
the Mother Helen Mohiam tells you.
你把我母亲当下人一样使唤
You dismiss my mother in her own house.
过来 跪下
Come here. Kneel.
你胆敢对我用“音言”
How dare you use the Voice on me?
把右手放进盒子里
Put your right hand in the box.
你母亲命你服从我
Your mother bade you obey me.
我在你脖子上握着戈姆刺 是一根毒针 瞬间致命
I hold at your neck the Gom Jabbar,
a poison needle, instant death.
测试很简单
The test is simple.
如果你把手从盒子中拿出来 就会死
Remove your hand
from the box, and you die.
盒子里有什么
What's in the box?
痛苦
Pain.
没必要叫侍卫
No need to call the guards.
你的母亲站在门外 没人能通过她
Your mother stands behind that door.
No one will get past her.
你为什么要这么做
Why are you doing this?
被陷阱捕获的动物 会咬断自己的腿逃生
An animal caught in a trap
will gnaw off its own leg to escape.
你会怎么做
What will you do?
住口
Silence.
我绝不能恐惧
I must not fear.
恐惧是思维的杀手
Fear is the mind-killer.
恐惧是潜伏的死神 会将人彻底毁灭
Fear is the little death
that brings obliteration.
我将直面恐惧 任它穿过我的身心
I will face my fear and I will permit it
to pass over me and through me.
当恐惧消逝
And when it has gone past…
我将睁开心灵之眼 看清它的轨道
I will turn the inner eye to see its path.
恐惧所到之处 万物无存
Where the fear has gone
there will be nothing.
唯我独在
Only I will remain.
够了
Enough.
我们筛人如沙
Like sifting sand through a screen,
we sift people.
如果你像牲畜一样不能控制自己的冲动
If you had been unable to control
your impulses like an animal,
我们不能让你活下去
we could not have let you live.
你继承了太多力量
You inherit too much power.
- 什么 因为我是公爵的儿子? - 因为你是杰西卡的儿子
-What, because I'm a Duke's son?
-Because you are Jessica's son.
你身负不只一种血脉 孩子
You have more than one birthright, boy.
杰西卡
Jessica.
你训练得法
You've been training him in a Way.
- 告诉我那些梦 - 我今晚刚做了一个
-Tell me about these dreams.
-I had one tonight.
你梦到了什么
What did you see?
- 厄拉科斯星球上的一个女孩 - 你以前梦到过她吗
-A girl on Arrakis.
-Have you dreamt of her before?
很多次
Many times.
你的梦境 会常在现实发生吗
Do you often dream things that happen
just as you dreamt them?
不完全
Not exactly.
再见 年轻人 我祝你健康
Goodbye, young human.
I hope you'll live.
一定要这样测试么
Did you have to go that far?
你选择训练他道法就违反了我们的规定
You chose to train him in the Way
in defiance of the rule.
他能用我们的法力 我一定要测试他的极限
He wields our power.
He had to be tested to the limits.
潜力无限 可惜浪费在一个男性上
So much potential wasted in the male.
你被告知只生女儿
You were told to bear only daughters,
可你却妄自尊大 以为可以生出魁萨茨·哈德拉克
but you and your pride thought
you could produce the Kwisatz Haderach.
我错了吗
Was I wrong?
他没死在那间房里算你幸运
You're lucky he didn't die in that room.
即使他是天选之子 也还有很长的路要走
If he is The One he has a long way to go.
他才刚刚觉醒而已 现在却要赴汤蹈火
His sight is barely awakened
and now he goes into the fire.
不过我们的计划是以千年来衡量的
But our plans are measured
in centuries.
如果他不能成功
We have other prospects
我们还另有预案
if he fails his promise.
你觉得希望如此渺茫
Do you see so little hope?
在厄拉科斯星球 我们已经为你竭尽所能
On Arrakis, we have done
all we can for you.
道路已经铺好 希望他不要辜负
The path has been laid.
Let's hope he doesn't squander it.
保罗
Paul…
那什么意思
What does it mean?
- 我会是天选之子吗? - 你听到了
-That I can be The One?
-You heard?
贝尼·杰瑟里特成为望族们的强大伙伴
The Bene Gesserit serve
as powerful partners to the great houses,
不是没有原因的
but there's more to it.
你们暗中操纵帝国政治
You stir the politics
on the Imperium from the shadows.
- 我知道 - 可你未尽其祥
-I know.
-You don't know everything.
千百年来
For thousands of years,
我们一直在小心翼翼地优配血统为了培育——
we've been carefully
crossing bloodlines to bring forth--
天选之子
The One?
一个先知
A mind…
强大到能够突破时间和空间 过去和未来
space and time, past and future…
powerful enough to breach
带领我们进入一个更美好的未来
who can help us into a better future.
我们认为他即将到来
We think he's very close now.
有人相信他就在这里
Some believe he is here.
全部都是计划
All part of the plan.
屏蔽场
Shields.
“吾入此时之息 出飘落之沙”
"My lungs taste the air of Time,
Blown past falling sands."
杜菲·哈瓦特
Thufir Hawat.
少主 走上新世界是何感觉
Young master, how does it feel
to walk on the new world?
难以言表 令人兴奋
Exciting, to say the least.
- 大人 - 你好吗 老朋友
-My Lord.
-How are you, old friend?
我的先遣队已经接管这座城市
My advance team has secured the city.
我们还在理顺一些棘手的地方
We're still smoothing out
a few rough spots.
夫人
My Lady.
利桑·阿尔·盖布
Lisan al-Gaib!
不要受欢迎所愚
Don't be fooled by the welcome.
他们遵循旧主规定 强制参加
They follow their old master's rules,
mandatory attendancy.
以前哈克南人的最爱
That's Harkonnen love out there.
厄崔迪
Atreides!
让我们尽快离开太阳底下
Let's get you out of the sun.
这个地方热得可以杀死人
The heat can kill in this place.
他们在说我们
They were pointing at us.
他们喊的是什么
What were they shouting?
利桑·阿尔·盖布 “天外之音”
Lisan al-Gaib.
"The Voice from the Outer World."
这是他们对“弥赛亚”的称呼
It's their name for "messiah."
这意味着贝尼·杰瑟里特在这儿做了一些工作
That means that Bene Gesserit
have done a work here.
散播迷信
Planting superstitions?
铺平道路 保罗
Preparing the way, Paul.
这些人已经等待了几个世纪的利萨·阿尔·盖布
These people have waited
for centuries for the Lisan al-Gaib.
他们看到了你 他们看到了征兆
They see you, they see the signs.
他们只看到别人告诉他们要看的东西
They see what they've been told to see.
我们准备好了
We're good to go.
屏蔽墙 保护城市免受天气和沙虫的侵害
Shield wall, protects the city
from the weather and the worms.
当地人把大的那个叫“上帝之手”
The locals call the big one
the "Hand of God."
上帝之手正在破坏我们的通讯系统
Well, the Hand of God
is wreaking havoc on our com system.
好安静啊
It's so quiet.
是的 这也是我担心的
Yeah. That's what worries me too.
那是太空港
There's a space port,
那边尘烟处是香料提炼厂
and in that plump of dust
there's a spice refinery.
我们最簿弱的两个点 我命令你死守此要地
Our two most vulnerable points.
I want you guarding them.
若我们不能提炼香料 运出外界 我们在此必死无疑
If we can't refine spice and ship it
off to the world, we're dead here.
太阳升高了 我们得封门
The sun is getting too high.
We need to seal the doors.
他们怎么说这个鬼地方来着?
What do they say
about this hell hole again?
“相当于洗澡时 你用沙子擦屁股”
"It's a shower, you scrub
your ass with sand,"
大人 他们是这么说的
My Lord, that's what they say.
他们是这么说的
That's what they say.
夫人 她们是应聘女管家的
Candidates for a house keeper, my lady.
- 你叫什么名字? - 夏道特·梅帕丝 夫人
-What is your name?
-Shadout Mapes, my lady.
其他人可以走了 谢谢
The rest of you may go. Thank you.
夏道特
Shadout.
这是古契科布萨语
It's an old chakobsa word.
意为舀井人
"Well dipper."
你是弗雷曼人
You are Fremen.
- 你懂古语? - 我知道很多东西
-You know the ancient tongues?
-I know many things.
我知道你们身体下藏着武器
I know that you have a weapon
concealed in your bodies.
等等
Wait.
如果你图谋不轨 我必须警告你不管你隐藏什么
If you mean to harm me,
I must warn you whatever you're hiding,
都于事无补
it won't be enough.
如果你是天选之子
My weapon is meant as a gift
我的武器就是礼物
if you are truly The One.
你知道这个吗
Do you know this?
晶牙匕
It's a crysknife.
你知道它什么意思吗
Do you know its meaning?
做好准备
Be ready.
它是沙漠之主
It's a maker.
一个沙漠深处的造物主
A maker of the deep desert.
一个人在预言中活得太久
When you have lived
with a prophecy for so long
等到启示之时必震惊不已
the moment of revelation is a shock.
利桑·阿尔·盖布 圣母和圣子
Lisan al-Gaib. The mother and the son.
献给你
It is yours.
夏胡鲁之牙
Tooth of Shai-Hulud.
你好
Hello.
你不应该在这个时候出来
You shouldn't be out here
at this time of the day.
他们也在外面
They are out here.
弗雷曼朝圣者 他们不在乎中暑
Fremen pilgrims.
They don't care about heat stroke.
我都不知道这里还有枣椰树
I didn't know date palms
could even be found out here.
他们不是土生土长的 没有我他们活不下去
These aren't indigenous.
They can't survive without me.
每棵树每天需要的水量相当于五个人
Each one of these drinks every day
the equivalent of five man.
二十棵棕榈树 一百条生命
Twenty palm trees. A hundred lives.
- 我们要把它们移走吗 节约用水 - 不 不
-Should we remove them? Save the water?
-No, no.
这些是神圣的
These are sacred.
旧梦
Old dream.
厄拉科斯星球上最大、最危险的生物是沙虫
The largest and the most dangerous
organism on Arrakis is the sandworm.
长度最长可达400米
Capable of reaching 400 meters in length.
为了避免发出有节奏的噪音吸引沙虫
To avoid making rhythmic noises
which attract the sandworms,
弗雷曼人走凌沙微步穿越沙漠
the Fremen cross desert spaces
using the sand walk,
模仿沙漠无规律的自然之声
a dance-like motion with irregular rhythm
犹如无节奏的舞蹈动作
which emulates the natural sounds
of the desert.
今天的厄拉科斯仍有植物全靠弗雷曼人
What scant plant life exists
on Arrakis is thanks to the Fremen,
他们一直在种植深入土壤的地球植物
who have cultivated
deep-rooted terrain plants,
例如仙人掌 驴灌木
such as saguaro, burrobush,
沙地马鞭草 以及香灌木
sand verbena and incense bush.
牧羊人树的树根是最长的
The shepherd's tree
has the deepest documented roots,
可以伸入超过450英尺深的地下
stretching more than 450 feet deep.
这些植物都可以在炎热且贫瘠的沙漠土地中生存
These plants cling to life
in a parched nutrient-poor landscape.
猎杀镖 刺客一定藏在附近
It's a hunter-seeker.
The operator must be nearby.
哈克南特工六周前用水泥固封在那个洞里
The Harkonnen agent was cemented
into that hole six weeks ago.
通过墙内的水管操纵猎杀镖
Manned the hunter-seeker
through a water pipe inside the walls.
陛下 我今日有辱使命 罪不容赦
Sir, I failed you today.
There's no excuse.
我向你请辞
You have my resignation.
- 你想让我们失去国之栋梁?  - 陛下 我的名誉要求
-You'd deprive us of your talents?
-Sir, my honor demands--
他们想要夺走我儿子的生命
They tried to take the life of my son!
我才不在乎你的名誉 你想要赦免 去抓刺客吧
I don't give a damn about your honor.
You want absolution? Go catch some spies.
陛下
Your Grace.
那东西必须离开
The thing must leave.
但说无妨 我们的宠物不懂你的语言
You can speak without fear.
Our pet doesn't understand your language.
滚
Get out!
它能理解 启动静默
It understands. Activate silence.
皇帝的旨意是什么
What is the Emperor's message?
他会派他的萨多卡军团
He will strengthen your hand.
助你一臂之力
With his Sardaukar army…
绝不许走漏风声
It must never be known.
厄拉科斯星球上没有卫星 厄崔迪家族将会死于黑暗
There's no satellites over Arrakis.
The Atreides would die in the dark.
关于这一点
On that matter.
雷托·厄崔迪公爵的死活对我们姐妹会毫无意义
Duke Leto Atreides
means nothing to our order.
但是他的妻子在我们保护之下 也包括她儿子
But his wife is under our protection,
and by extension, her son.
给他们放逐的尊严
Allow them the dignity of exile.
哈克南家族绝不会违反姐妹会神圣的命令
House Harkonnen would never dream
of violating the sanctity of your order.
我向你保证 我们不会伤害他们
I give you my word.
We would not harm them.
- 如果公爵的儿子还活着 - 厄崔迪将不复存在
-If the Duke's son lives--
-No Atreides will live.
大人 你向女巫保证过了 她无所不知
My Lord, you gave your word to the witch.
And she sees too much.
我说过不会伤害他们 就不会伤害他们
I said I would not harm them.
And I shall not.
但厄拉科斯是厄拉科斯
But Arrakis is Arrakis,
沙漠会吞噬弱者
and the desert takes the weak.
我的沙漠
My desert.
我的厄拉科斯
My Arrakis.
我的沙丘
My dune.
你的第一次战略会议
Your first strategy meeting.
保罗·厄崔迪赤手空拳抓住猎杀镖 就像古代英雄一样
Paul Atreides, who catches hunter-seekers
in his bare hands like a hero of all.
- 谢谢你的羞辱 老家伙 - 我会看着你的
-Thanks for the humiliation, old man.
-I'll keep an eye on you.
立正
Attention!
我们开始吧
Let's get started.
杜菲 你先来
Thufir, operations.
我弄到了一份哈克南的账本
I've secured a copy
of the Harkonnen's account books.
哈克南人每年从这里带走100亿索拉里斯
The Harkonnens were taking 10 billion
solaris out of here every year.
“因其必夺 海之丰裕
"They shall suck at the abundance
of the seas
沙之珍宝”
and on the treasures hidden in the sand."
靠他们留下来的设备
We won't see profits
like that for a while,
我们一时做不到如此大的利润
not with the equipment they left us.
情况有多糟
How bad is it?
这里是香料贮窖
These are spice silos.
我们必须装满每一个筒仓
We are meant to fill every crate.
全部
All of them?
每25个标准日（一次）
Every 25 standard days.
哈克南人暗中破坏阻碍了我们
Harkonnen sabotage slows us down.
那谁来仲裁呢
But who's meant to arbitrate?
难道没有一个星变裁判官来监督移交吗
Isn't there a Judge of the Change
to oversee the transition?
- 皇帝任命了谁  - 帝国生态学家列特·凯恩斯博士
-Who did the Emperor appoint?
-Dr. Liet Kynes, imperial ecologist.
在此地已待20年 据我所知 性情古怪
Been here 20 years.
Eccentric from what I'm told.
我想去采集香料的地方亲眼看看
I want to see
these harvesting fields myself.
请慎重 大人
I wouldn't recommend it, my lord.
让这位星变裁判官陪伴我们
Have this Judge of the Change
accompany us.
我们早该见面了
Our meeting is long overdue.
我们会得到一些帝国的保护
And we'll get a bit
of imperial protection.
人质 我喜欢
A hostage? I love it.
他来了 大人
He's here, my lord
照顾好他们 他们是朋友
Take care of them, they are friends.
- 邓肯! - 好小子
-Duncan!
-My boy!
- 我敢说你长高了 - 是的 你怎么臭哄哄的
-I swear you're getting taller.
-Well, you smell much worse.
我和弗雷曼人生活了四个星期
For four weeks I've lived with the Fremen,
住在一个隐藏在沙漠中 叫做穴地的部落里
hidden in the desert,
in the community called the sietch.
斯蒂尔格 那个穴地部落的首领跟我一起来见你 陛下
Stilgar, the leader of that sietch
has come with me to meet you, sir.
- 这个穴地部落藏在哪里 - 地下
-This sietch, how was it hidden?
-It's under ground.
厄拉科斯遍布地穴
Arrakis is filled with caverns.
那地方有多大
How big was the place?
我估计能住一万人 而穴地又有数百之多
It's a ten thousand people,
and there are hundreds of sietches.
上百万弗雷曼人 你是对的
Millions of Fremen. You were right.
哈克南人估计整个星球上只有五万人
The Harkonnen estimate
was fifty thousand on the whole planet.
弗雷曼人观察我找寻他们数日 我却从未发现他们
The Fremen watched me search
for them for days. I never saw them.
终于 他们派出一名战士要杀我
Finally, they sent
a warrior out to kill me,
说实话 我差一点就死了
and I have to tell you,
I've never come so close to dying.
帝国没有比这更好的战士
There's no finer fighter in the Imperium.
- 他们浴血奋战 - 沙漠力量
-They fight like demons.
-Desert power.
- 邓肯 干得好 - 谢谢 大人
-Duncan, well done.
-Thank you, my lord.
陛下 他们的首领有一把刀不肯上缴 陛下
Sir, their leader has a knife
he won't surrender, sir.
晶牙匕 是他们的圣物
It's a crysknife,
it's sacred to his people.
让他过来
Let him pass.
站住
Stop there.
嘿! 嘿
Hey! Hey!
斯蒂尔格 欢迎
Stilgar, welcome.
先生 我很尊重那些愿意尊重我的人
Sir, I respect the personal dignity
of any man that respects mine.
等一下
Hold.
感谢您 斯蒂尔格 用你生命之水作为见面礼
Thank you, Stilgar, for the gift
of your body's moisture.
我们接受你的这份诚意
We accept it in the spirit
in which it was given.
你登门造访 我喜不自胜
I'm glad you've come.
我想 你我两族人 能礼尚往来
I believe your people and mine
have much to offer one another.
你们这些异星人 你们来这里是为了香料
You are outworlders,
you come here for the spice,
你们拿走它 却不付出任何回报
You take it, giving nothing in return.
这是真的
That's true.
我深知你族 苦于哈克南
I know you've suffered
at the hands of the Harkonnen.
你有求我应
Name what you want.
必力所能及 并不取分文
If it's in my power to grant
I'll give it and ask for nothing.
我请求你们不要滋扰我们的部族 不要侵入我们的领土
I ask for this: do not seek our sietches,
do not trespass in our lands.
早在你们来之前 沙漠就是我们的
The desert was ours long before you came.
所以 来挖你们的香料吧
So, come and dig your spice,
但挖到以后 滚回屏蔽墙的另一边
but when you have it,
go back to this side of the shield wall
把沙漠留给弗雷曼人
and leave the desert to the Fremen.
你要称呼公爵为“大人”或“陛下”
You will address the Duke
as "my lord," or "sir."
哥尼 等一下
Gurney, just… Just a moment.
皇帝赐厄拉科斯 封为我地 护国佑民
The Emperor has given me Arrakis
as my fief to rule and protect.
我有责在身 难以保证不过沙漠
I cannot promise not to travel
into the desert if duty compels me.
但所有穴地 必是你们的
But your sietches will be yours forever.
在我执政期内 你们必安然无恙
and you will never be hunted
while I govern here.
我钦佩你的承诺
That's very honorable.
我得走了
I must go.
我要说的就是这些
That's all I have to say to you.
你不留下么 我们很荣幸
Why don't you stay.
We would honor you.
我的使命不在这里
Honor requires that I be elsewhere.
我认得你
I know who you are.
- 我不喜欢他 - 我们的计划有成果了
-I don't like him.
-Our plan bears fruit.
但需要时间
But it will take time.
是的 需要时间
Yes. It will take time.
给你的
Here, this is for you.
定位罗盘
It's a paracompass.
这的卫星有磁场 普通的指南针不能指北
The moons here have a magnetic field, so
a simple compass needle won't point north.
就要这一精密仪器来处理
Takes a clever piece
of clockwork to sort it out.
都是弗雷曼人造的吗
Do Fremen make these?
还有蒸馏服 沙压器 各种各样的精巧发明
And stillsuits, and sand compactors,
and all kinds of ingenious things.
沙压器是什么鬼东西
What the hell is a sand compactor?
这就是沙压器
That's a sand compactor.
我的天啊 伙计 你变本地人了
My God, man, you've gone native.
你钦佩他们
You admire them.
是的
I do.
他们赤胆忠心
They're fierce but loyal.
他们熟知沙漠 这些还只是他们的一小部分
They're tuned into the desert,
part of it, it's part of them.
等你在外面见到他们
You wait till you see it.
就懂得他们的美
It's beautiful out there.
日出警告
Sunrise warning.
气温将升至140度 现在是90度
…The temperature up to 140 degrees.
The temperature now is 90 degrees.
但将在10分钟内上升50度
But it will rise
50 degrees in ten minutes.
最后警告
Last warning.
星变裁判官 陛下
The Judge of the Change, sir.
列特·凯恩斯博士
Dr. Liet Kynes.
大人 公爵 欢迎来到厄拉科斯
My Lord, Duke, welcome to Arrakis.
你是帝国的生态学家
You are the imperial ecologist.
谢谢你的蒸馏服
Thank you for the stillsuits.
这些是弗雷曼人造的最好的
They are Fremen make, the best.
陛下 如果您容许 我必须检查一下是否穿戴完好
With your permission, sir,
I must check the integrity--
没关系
It's all right.
凯恩斯博士 悉听尊便
Dr. Kynes, we're in your hands.
一件蒸馏服是一套高效的过滤系统
A stillsuit is a high-efficiency
filtration system.
即使是在凌晨
Even this early in the morning
没有这些东西 你也活不过两个小时
you wouldn't survive
two hours without one of these.
它能使身体降温 并回收出汗而流失的水分
It cools the body and recycles
the water lost to sweat.
身体运动就提供动能
Your bodies movements provide the power.
在面具里面 你会发现一个管子 让你可以喝回收的水
Inside the mask you'll find a tube
to allow you to drink the recycled water.
在正常工作状态下 你的蒸馏服每天损失的水不会超过一点点
In good-working order your suit won't lose
more than a thimble full of water a day.
真历害
Most impressive.
让我看看你 小伙子
Let's have a look at you, lad.
- 你以前穿过蒸馏服吗? - 没有 我第一次穿
-You've worn a stillsuit before?
-No, this is my first time.
你的沙地靴脚踝那儿的松紧带箍得正好 谁教你的
Your desert boots off at a slip fashion
at the ankles. Who taught you to do that?
感觉这是正确之道
It seemed the right way.
“此乃正道 与生俱来 你应知道 出神入化”
"He will know his customs
as if he was born with them."
你是弗雷曼人吗?
Are you a Fremen?
我在穴地和乡村都被接受
I am accepted in both sietch and village.
现在
Now.
来看看诸位赖以生存的香料沙田吧
Come and see the spice sands
on which your livelihood depends.
如果你的扑翼机掉到这里 你怎么办
What would you do if your ornithopter
went down out here?
最好想都别想 那是沙虫之地
You wouldn't want to go down out there.
It's worm territory.
沙尘云
Dust cloud.
我看到了
I see it.
那是你的一台香料机车
That's one of your harvesters.
你可以看到香料散落在表面
You can see the spice
scattered over the surface.
从颜色判断 这里是香料的富矿床
Rich spice bed by the color.
再爬高一点 视野会更好
If you get a little higher
you'll have a better view.
你能看到侦察机 正在寻找虫迹
You see these spotter aircraft
looking for worm sign.
什么虫迹
Worm sign?
一阵向香料机车移动的沙浪
A sand wave moving toward the crawler.
沙虫虽然潜伏得很深 但它们要发动攻击时会逐渐浮到地表
Worms travel deep but get closer
to the surface when they attack.
如果你们有耐心 应该能看到
If you are patient we should see one.
- 沙虫会来么  - 一定会 它们总是被有节奏的噪音吸引
-Worm always comes?
-Always, they're drawn by rhythmic noises.
为什么不给香料机车安装屏蔽场呢
Why don't we just shield the crawlers?
在沙漠里用屏蔽场无异死路一条
A shield is a death sentence
in the desert.
屏蔽场不仅吸引沙虫 更使其极度狂暴
It attracts the worms
and drives them into a killing frenzy.
那是沙虫吗
Is that a worm?
一条大虫
Big one.
好眼力
You have good eyes.
呼叫DA9号机车 虫迹警告 听到请回答
Calling crawler Delta Ajax 9.
Worm sign warning. Acknowledge.
谁呼叫DA9号  完毕
Who calls Delta Ajax 9? Over.
- 他们好象很淡定啊 - 临时飞行 处理帝国事务
-They seem pretty calm about it.
-Unlisted flight, Imperium business.
虫迹在东北方3.7公里
Worm sign, north and east of you.
3.7 kilometers.
DA9号 我是侦察1号 确认虫迹
Delta Ajax 9, this is Spotter 1,
worm sighting confirmed.
稍后确认到达时间
Standby for contact fix.
沙虫正在快速奔向你处 5分钟后到达
Worm is on intercept course
to your position. Contact in five minutes.
现在怎么办
So what happens now?
他们准备呼叫大型运载机去回收香料机车
They'll call the carryall
to lift the crawler.
他们会采集到最后一刻
They'll harvest right up
to the last minute.
呼叫阿尔法零号大型运载机 准备对接程序
Calling carryall Alfa Zero.
Ready to docking sequence.
沙虫五分钟后到达 完毕
Contact five minutes, over.
有人看见大型运载机么
Anybody got a visual on a carryall?
来了
There it is.
DA9号 这是大型运载机阿尔法零号
This is carryall Alfa Zero
to Delta Ajax 9.
从你的东面接近
Approaching from your east.
校正高度 准备对接和抓取
Correcting altitude and preparing
docking and gripping.
收到 阿尔法零号 开始对接程序
Copy, Alpha Zero.
Initiating docking sequence.
- T-5 - 收到
-T-5.
-Copy that.
- 准备30秒后升空 - 启动对接程序
-Prepare to be airborne in 30 seconds.
-Docking sequence initiated.
做好准备
Brace yourselves.
阿尔法零号 有一个支点未连接
Alpha Zero, we are short
on one point of contact.
- 怎么回事 - 有个锚坏了
-What is going on?
-It's one of the anchors. It's dead.
该死
Shit.
大型运载机不能继续 没有锚就无法起飞
Carryall, unable to proceed.
Unable to lift without that anchor.
全体 全体
All call. All call.
此区的全体大型运载机请回复
Any carryall in the sector,
please respond.
侦察员1号 报告最新情况 完毕
Spotter 1, give us an update. Over.
液压系统坏了 无法修复 尽快撤离
Hydraulics are dead.
We won't make it. You have to evacuate.
- 香料机车上有多少人 - 21个
-How many men on that crawler?
-Crawler of 21.
- 我们飞船每艘可以载六个人 - 还差三个人
-Our ships can take six each.
-That's still three short.
我们会找到解决之道的
We'll find a way.
这是雷托·厄崔迪公爵
This is Duke Leto Atreides.
我们准备下来带走DA9号的人
We're coming down
to extract the crew of Delta Ajax 9.
所有人集中左侧
Sit down on the left.
一台屏蔽场发生器重达一百公斤
The shield generators
weigh 100 kilos each.
好 哥尼 让侍卫扔掉屏蔽场发生器
Yes, Gurney, have our escort
throw out the shield generators.
保罗 我要你在扑翼机后面 指挥他们进来
And Paul, I want you at the back
of the thopter, guide them in.
DA9号 立刻在我们的飞船上各安排7个人
Delta Ajax 9, put seven
men each in my ships now.
沙虫两分钟后到达
Contact in two minutes.
快来了 伙计们 我们最好现在弃船
It's getting close, guys.
We better abandon the ship now.
他们在哪儿
Where are they?
陛下 这是有规定的
Sir, there is protocol for a reason,
只要我们跨出一步 我们就死定了
if we take one step out
we're as good as dead.
另外 我们装满了香料 不能就这样离开
Besides, we've got full load
of spice, we can't just leave--
该死的香料 我要所有人立刻离开香料机车
Damn the spice! I want
every man off that crawler now!
七个这边 七个那边
Seven over here, seven over there!
快跑 快跑
Run, run!
魁萨茨·哈德拉克
Kwisatz Haderach.
魁萨茨·哈德拉克醒了
Kwisatz Haderach awakes.
快点 上车
Hurry! Get on!
在这里
It's here!
保罗
Paul!
我认得你的脚步声 老家伙
I recognize your footsteps, old man.
起来 我们走
Get up. Let's go.
你怎么了 快点 我们走
What's wrong with you?
Come on. Let's go.
快跑
Run!
“赞美主和它的水 赞美它降临逝去
"Bless the Maker and His water.
Bless the coming and going of Him.
愿它所到之处 净化大地 为民护地”
May His passage cleanse the world.
And keep the world for His people."
- 嘿 你不能这样冒险 - 是的 陛下
-Hey, you cannot take such risks.
-Yes, sir.
- 你有责任 - 我很抱歉 陛下 下不为例
-You do have responsibilities.
-I'm sorry, sir. It won't happen again.
凯恩斯博士
Dr. Kynes.
你亲眼所见
You saw it with your own eyes.
很明显 他们留给我们的一团糟
It's plain to see. Everything
they've left us is in shambles.
我们注定要失败
We've been set up to fail.
那辆大型运载机太旧了 沙漠对设备并不友善
That carryall was just old.
The desert isn't kind to equipment.
你知道如果我不让香料生产回到正轨会发生什么吗
You know what will happen if I don't get
spice production back on track?
我不是来帮你的
I'm not here to take your part.
厄拉科斯见证了像你这样的人来来去去
Arrakis has seen men like you come and go.
好好照顾你的家人
Take good care of your family.
沙漠对人类也不友善
The desert's not kind to humans either.
香料是一种影响精神活动的物质 你好象对它很敏感
Spice is a psychoactive chemical.
You seem to be sensitive.
并无大碍
You'll be fine.
谢谢你 岳医生
Thank you, Dr. Yueh.
这不是过敏反应
It wasn't an allergic reaction.
我看见一个幻象
I had a vision.
我睁大眼睛看
My eyes were wide open.
你看到了什么
What did you see?
魁萨茨·哈德拉克
Kwisatz Haderach...
你可以看到
You can see.
梦境很混乱 我好像看到我死了 但又不是
It's confusing, I thought
I saw my death, only it wasn't.
不知为何 有一把刀很重要
I know a knife is important somehow.
有人递给我一把刀
Someone will hand me a blade.
但我不知道是何人 何时 何地
But I don't know who or when or where.
可又有一些事我心里很清楚 我能感受到
Some things though
are crystal clear. I can feel it.
我知道你怀孕了
I know you're pregnant.
你不可能知道
You can't know that.
我自己也才刚知道 不过几周而已
I barely know that
and it's only been few weeks.
萨卢萨二号帝国陆军行星
男爵为何需要我们
What does the Baron want with us?
哈克南家族的兵力远超厄崔迪家族
The Harkonnen outnumber Atreides.
厄崔迪军团勇冠帝国
Atreides legions are the finest
in the Imperium.
由哥尼·哈勒克和邓肯·爱达荷训练
Trained by Gurney Halleck
and Duncan Idaho.
我们是萨多卡军团 帝霸出征 寸草不生
We are the Sardaukar, the Emperor's elite.
Anyone who defies us will fall.
没错
Just so.
三个营 说好的
Three battalions as agreed.
诏之即来 战之必胜
As the the Emperor commands.
It will be done.
有些关于保罗的事你需要知道
There's something you need
to know about Paul.
不 我不想知道
No. I don't think I wanna know.
自从你带他见圣母后
Ever since you brought him before
your Reverend Mother
他像变了个人
he hasn't been the same.
他心烦意乱
He's distracted.
杰西卡 你给了我一个儿子
Jessica, you gave me a son.
从他出生的那一刻起我就不曾质疑你
And from the moment he was born
I never questioned you.
我完全信任你 即使你背着我行事
I trusted you completely,
even when you walked in shadows.
现在我只问你一件事
Now I'm asking you this one thing.
如果我有任何不测 你会保护我们的儿子吗
If anything happens
will you protect our son?
不惜生命
With my life.
我不是在问他的母亲 我是在问贝尼·杰瑟里特
I'm not asking his mother,
I'm asking the Bene Gesserit.
你会保护保罗吗
Will you protect Paul?
你为什么想这些
Why are you having these thoughts?
雷托 这不像你
Leto, this is not you.
我以为我们还有时间
I thought we'd have more time.
- 晚安 保罗少主 - 晚安 岳医生
-Have a good night, Master Paul.
-Good night, Dr. Yueh.
你需要好好睡一觉
You need to sleep.
不 不要那个
No, not like that.
我真应该娶你
I should have married you.
哈瓦特 叫侍卫
Hawat. Security.
侍卫
Security!
长官 长官
Sir. Sir.
屏蔽墙关闭了
The shield's come down.
老天在上
God in Heaven.
所有飞行器起飞 快
Get everything with guns
off the ground! Go!
跟我来
With me!
厄崔迪
Atreides!
萨多卡
Sardaukar!
对不起 大人
I'm sorry, my lord.
但我已和男爵达成了协议
But I've made a bargain with the Baron.
- 为什么? - 我别无选择
-Why?
-I had no choice.
哈克南人绑架了我的妻子 万娜
The Harkonners have my wife, Wanna.
他们把她像玩具一样肢解
They take her apart like a doll.
我想换取她的自由 而你就是代价
I will buy her freedom
and you are the price.
我会竭尽所能交给保罗
For Paul. I will do what I can.
而你要为我杀死一人
And you will kill a man for me.
我会替换你的锥形牙
I'm going to replace your peg tooth.
只要你用力一咬 这颗牙就会碎裂
If you bite them hard,
this tooth will crash.
呼气 空气中就充满了毒素
Breathe out, and you will fill
the air with poison.
这将是你的最后一口气
It will be your last breath.
但是如果你的时机选择得好
But if you choose your moment well
它也将是男爵的最后一口
it will also be the Baron's.
保罗
Paul.
我们一会把他们扔进沙漠 丢给沙虫
We will drop them in the desert,
and leave them to the worms.
为何不直接割喉杀掉
Why not just cut their throats?
要是真言师问起这事
They might use a Truthsayer.
我们就可以说没有杀他们
Then we can honestly say
that we didn't kill them.
那个疤脸是聋子
The one with the scar is deaf.
去死吧 狗
To hell, dogs!
我从来没搞过一个贵族
I've never had a high-born.
- 你呢? - 贝尼·杰瑟里特不算贵族
-You?
-Bene Gesserit ain't no high-born.
她出身高贵 对我来说足够了
She is high-born enough for me.
把这小孩拿去喂沙虫 让他们母子永别
Let's feed the kid to the worms
and give her a long goodbye.
你敢碰我母亲试试
Don't you dare touch my mother.
别说话
Don't talk.
不 你还没准备好
No. You're not ready.
拿开她的嘴塞
Remove her gag.
闭嘴
Shut up.
找到正确的音调
Find the right tone.
我们够远了 把男孩扔下去
We're far enough.
Let's throw the boy off.
拿开她的嘴塞
Remove her gag.
杀了他
Kill him.
放开我们
Set us free.
停 割断绳子
Stop. Cut the rope.
把刀给我
Give me the knife.
你的音调太生硬了
Your pitch was too forced.
这是一个弗雷曼生存包
It's a Fremkit.
他们破坏了飞船
They've crippled the ship.
你的厨房真好 表弟
You have a wonderful kitchen, cousin.
这是岳医生的笔迹
This is Dr. Yueh's handwriting.
“如果有人活着逃出厄拉科斯 生存包里有厄崔迪的信号器
"If anyone makes it out of Arrakeen alive
there's an Atreides beacon in the Fremkit.
上帝保佑他们找到你”
God willing they'd be able to find you."
男爵大人 岳医生
Milord Baron, Dr. Yueh.
叛徒
The traitor?
你有何求
What do you want?
我切断通讯 关闭屏蔽墙
I jammed their comms
and lowered their shields.
我把公爵和他的家人送来
I gave you Duke and his family.
谈条件爽快点 你有何求于我
The bargain to the letter.
And what was I to do for you?
释放我饱受痛苦的妻子
Deliver my wife from her agony.
啊 好
Yes.
我承诺过我会还她自由 那你才能与她重聚
I said I'd set her free,
that you could join her.
与她重聚吧
So join her.
你认为接下来会发生什么
What do you think is next?
一个沙槌
It's a thumper.
没有蒸馏服
No stillsuits.
那才是我们真正需要的
The one thing we actually need.
数个世纪以来 我们血债血偿
For hundreds of years
we've traded blood for blood.
但日后不再
But no more.
你儿子死了 你的妾也死了
Your son is dead. Your concubine is dead.
今晚厄崔迪家族陨落
Tonight the house Atreides falls…
你家血脉从此终结
and your bloodline ends forever.
你刚才说什么
What did you say?
“我在此 我存在”
"Here I am, here I remain!"
- 凯恩斯! - 你在这里不安全
-Kynes!
-It's not safe for you here.
你能告诉兰兹拉德最高委员会我们是怎样被出卖的吗
Will you tell the Great House
of the Landsraad how we were betrayed?
他们中最优秀的是如何被谋杀的
How the best of them were murdered?
我奉命闭口不谈 视若不见
I am commanded to say nothing,
to see nothing.
皇帝是让我们来这送死
The Emperor sent us here to die.
帐蓬里有香料
Spice in the tank.
这就是未来 它即将到来
That's the future. It's coming.
圣战像不灭的火焰一样蔓延整个宇宙
The Holy war is spreading across
the universe like an unquenchable fire.
保罗 你害怕了 我看得出来 告诉我 你害怕什么
Paul, you're scared. I can see it.
Tell me, please, what do you fear?
- 谁来帮帮我 - 保罗
-Somebody help me, please.
-Paul…
未来已来
It's coming.
圣战像不灭的火焰一样蔓延整个宇宙
The Holy war is spreading across
the universe like an unquenchable fire.
一个以我父亲的名义高举厄崔迪旗帜的好战宗教
A warrior religion that waves
the Atreides banner in my father's name.
狂战军团 在我父亲的遗骸圣殿中膜拜
Fanatical legions worshiping
at the shine of my father's skull.
以我的名义发动战争! 每个人都在喊我的名字
A war in my name!
Everyone shouting my name!
保罗
Paul.
保罗·厄崔迪
Paul Atreides…
你是你父亲的儿子 你是我的儿子
You are your father's son.
You are my son.
你现在是保罗·厄崔迪公爵
You are Duke Paul Atreides.
你知道你是谁
You know who you are.
放开我
Get off me!
你造就了我你们贝尼·杰瑟里特把我变成怪胎
You did this to me!
Your Bene Gesserit made me a freak!
我父已死
My father is dead.
有人在附近
Someone is near.
你需要喝水
You need to drink.
这是帐篷里的循环水
It's recycled water from the tent.
来自汗水和眼泪
Sweat and tears.
好了 我们走吧
All right. Let's get out of here.
是邓肯
It's Duncan.
夫人 保罗
My Lady. Paul…
- 我很抱歉 你父亲 - 我们知道了
-I'm so sorry… Your father…
-We know.
公爵大人
My Lord Duke.
给你
Here.
把这个喝了
Drink this.
哈克南人同时对星球上的每一个人口聚集处发动袭击
The Harkonnens hit every population
center on the planet at once.
他们一定出动了十个军团 数百艘飞船
It must've been ten legions,
hundreds of ships.
萨多卡和他们一起
There were Sardaukar with them.
- 至少两个营 - 你确定
-At least two battalions.
-Are you sure?
只要你和他们交过手 就知道
You cross swords
with the Sardaukar, you know it.
那么说 皇帝要对付我们
So, the Emperor's taken a side.
星变裁判官怎么说
What says the Judge of the Change?
皇帝禁止我说任何话
The Emperor forbids me
from saying anything at all.
但你冒生命危险来帮我们
Yet you risk your life to help us.
沙暴就要来了
The storm is coming.
沙暴几小时后就会到 我们在这里很安全
The storm will be here in a few hours.
We'll be safe here.
你知道这是什么地方吗? 一个早年建造的生态试验站
Do you know what this place is?
It's an old ecological testing station.
他们本想改造这颗星球
The were meant to tame the planet
释出沙子下面的水
and free the water locked
beneath the sands.
厄拉科斯本可以成为天堂
Arrakis could have been a paradise.
然而工程刚开始 就发现了香料
The work had begun
but then the spice was discovered.
突然之间 没有一个人希望沙漠消失
and suddenly no one wanted
the desert to go away.
塔纳特 你能给我们的访客找几套蒸馏服么
Tanat, will you find
stillsuits to fit our visitors.
是的 列特
Yes, Liet.
- 沙米尔 上几杯咖啡 - 好的 列特
-Shamir, coffee service, please.
-Of course, Liet.
你是弗雷曼的什么人
Who are you to the Fremen?
你知道望族最害怕什么吗 凯恩斯博士
Do you know what the great houses
fear most, Dr. Kynes?
就是这里发生的一切
Exactly what has happened to us here.
被皇帝的萨多卡军团各个击破
The Sardaukar coming
and picking them off one by one.
只有团结一致 他们才有一线希望对抗帝国
Only together can they stand a chance
against the Imperium.
你愿意作证吗
Would you bare witness?
证明皇帝在这里对我们做的一切
Testify that the Emperor
has moved against us here.
如果他们相信我
If they believe me…
望族和皇帝之间将会发生全面战争
There would be general warfare
between the great houses and the Emperor.
混乱会蔓延整个帝国
Chaos across the Imperium.
但假设我给皇帝一个混乱之外的选择
Let's suppose I present to the Emperor
with an alternative to chaos.
皇帝没有儿子 只有尚待出嫁的女儿
And the Emperor has no sons,
and his daughters are yet to marry.
你想上演权力的游戏
You'd make a play for the throne?
皇帝惧怕厄崔迪家族 让你们来这就是为了斩草除根
The Emperor feared the Atreides.
He brought you here to kill you.
你还不明白吗
What don't you understand?
你就像一个躲在地洞里迷路的男孩
You're a lost boy hiding
in a hole in the ground.
弗雷曼人称我为利桑·阿尔·盖布
The Fremen speak of the Lisan al-Gaib.
小心点
Careful.
“天外之音”将引领他们进入天堂
The Voice from the Outer World
who will lead them to paradise.
迷信
Superstition.
我知道你爱过一个弗雷曼战士 在战斗中失去了他
I know you loved a Fremen warrior
and lost him in battle.
我知道你穿行两个世界 且以不同的名字为人熟知
I know you walk in two worlds
and are known by many names.
我知道你的梦想
I've seen your dream.
若我作皇帝 凯恩斯博士
As Emperor, Dr. Kynes,
只要我一挥手 就可以给你一个天堂般的厄拉科斯
I could make a paradise for Arrakis
with the wave of my hand.
你真的认为他会是马赫迪吗
Do you really think he could be the Mahdi?
他看起来太年轻了
He looks very young.
萨多卡!
Sardaukar!
- 不! 邓肯! - 保罗 不
-No! Duncan!
-Paul, no!
- 邓肯 不! - 他把门锁上了
-Duncan, no!
-He's locked the door.
他死了
He's gone.
邓肯
Duncan!
我们必须走 我们别无选择
We have to go. We have no choice.
保罗 快跑
Paul, run!
快点 快点
Come on, come on!
跟着光走 会发现一架扑翼机 随时可以起飞
Follow the light. You'll find
a thopter ready to fly.
外面的沙暴是你最好的机会
That storm out there
is your best shot.
沙暴超过五千米高 大部分是沙尘 飞上去 保持高度
Above 5000 meters, it's mostly dust.
Climb into it. Stay on top.
- 一直往南 去找弗雷曼人 - 你不跟我们一起走吗
-Head south. Find the Fremen.
-You're not coming with us?
只有两个座位
It only sits two.
我会去下一个试验站 向兰兹拉德最高委员会报告这次袭击
I'll go to the next station
and report this attack to the Landsraad.
怎么去?
How?
我是弗雷曼人 沙漠是我家
I'm Fremen. The desert is my home.
- 好运 - 好运
-Good luck.
凯恩斯 你背叛了皇帝
Kynes, you have betrayed the emperor.
我只侍奉一位主人
I serve only one master.
他的名字叫夏胡鲁
His name is Shai-Hulud.
我们后面有喷气机
There are jet flyers behind us.
保罗 我们还不够高
Paul, we are not high enough!
我绝不能恐惧 恐惧是思维的杀手
I must not fear. Fear is the mind-killer.
恐惧是潜伏的死神 会将人彻底毁灭
Fear is the little-death
that brings total obliteration.
去见朋友
See the friend.
人生的奥秘并不是一个需要解决的问题
The mystery of life
isn't a problem to solve.
而是一个需要体验的现实
But a reality to experience.
一个不能通过停止来理解的过程
A process that cannot be understand
by stopping it.
我们必须随着进程的流动而前进
We must move with the flow
of the process.
我们必须加入它 我们必须随着它沉浮
We must join it.
We must float with it.
放手 放手
Let it go. Let it go.
他还没有完全康复
He hasn't fully healed yet.
我们追杀他们进入科里奥利风暴
We chased them into a Coriolis storm.
风速每小时800公里
Wind's at 800 kilometers an hour.
没有人能在这样的风暴中幸存
Nothing survives such a storm.
他们必死无疑
They're dead. It's a certainty.
总算完成了
So it's done finally.
向杰迪主星发消息 开始卖我们库存的香料
Send word to Giedi Prime
to begin selling our spice reserves.
慢点卖 我们不希望价格下跌
But slowly.
We don't want the price to fall.
你无法想象 我将这样的军力运上前线 要花多少钱
You have no idea how much it cost me
to bring such a force to barrier.
现在我只有一个要求 收入
Now I only have one requirement. Income.
去榨干他们 拉班 使劲榨
So, squeeze, Rabban. Squeeze hard.
是的 叔叔
Yes, uncle.
那弗雷曼人呢
And the Fremen?
统统杀光
Kill them all.
我们在5000米以上
We're above 5000 meters.
我们一着陆 就向岩石跑
As soon as we land, run for the rocks.
用这个来呼吸
You breathe with this.
现在我们必须找到弗雷曼人
Now we have to find the Fremen.
- 你没事吧  - 没事
-Are you good?
-Yeah.
保罗
Paul…
不要害怕
Don't be frightened.
即使是沙漠里的小老鼠也能活下来
Even a little desert mouse can survive.
你需要直面你的恐惧
You'll need to face your fears.
一个朋友会帮助你
A friend will help you.
跟着那位朋友
Follow the friend.
你还有很多东西要学
You have much to learn.
我将指引你沙漠之道
And I will show you
the ways of the desert.
跟我走吧
Come with me.
邓肯住过的穴地部落
The sietch, where Duncan lived.
应该就在前边
Somewhere off that way.
我可以看到绿色植被
I can see the green over there.
在那儿
There.
说明弗雷曼人就住在那里
That means Fremen live there.
我们天黑后过去 弗雷曼人就是这么做的
We'll cross after dark.
That's how the Fremen do it.
我们即将进入沙虫之地
We're about to enter worm territory.
我们不能像正常人一样行走 不然我们就死定了
We can't walk like regular humans,
if we do - we're dead.
我们必须像弗雷曼人那样走路 这叫凌沙微步
We'll have to walk like the Fremen do.
It's called the sand walk.
至少家里的胶片书是这么说的
At least according
to the film books back home.
是的 是的 我知道了
Yeah. Yeah, I've got it.
好 跟着我 做同样的动作
Okay, follow me. Do the same moves.
我认为这是正确的方向
I think this is the right direction.
就在附近 我们走吧
It's close by. Let's get out of here.
等等
Wait.
这是鼓沙
It's drum sand.
快跑
Run!
跑 跑
Go! Go!
沙槌
It's a thumper.
有人启动了沙槌
Someone set off a thumper.
保罗 快跑
Paul, run!
它们有多大 简直疯了
How big are they? That was insane.
有人引开了他
Someone called him.
这里还有别人
We are not alone.
别跑
Do not run.
只会浪费身体的水
You will only waste your bodies water.
等等
Hold.
斯蒂尔格
Stilgar.
你认识我 你来参加我父亲的会议时我在场
Hey, you know me. I was there
when you came to my father's council.
他是公爵的儿子
This is the Duke's son.
你还等什么 我们需要他们的水
Why are you waiting?
We need their water.
这就是我跟你说过的那个男孩 我们不能碰他
This is the boy I told you about.
We can't touch him.
- 他是利桑·阿尔·盖布吗 - 他还没有证明自己
-Is he Lisan al-Gaib?
-He hasn't proved himself.
- 他们是弱者 - 詹米
-They're weaklings.
-Jamis…
他们勇敢地在沙虫之地闯出一条道路
There was a brave crossing
they made in the path of Shai-Hulud.
他的言行举止不像一个弱者
He does not speak
or act like a weakling.
他的父亲也一样
Nor did his father.
我的沙槌救了他的命
My thumper saved his life.
醒醒吧 斯蒂尔格 他不是天选之子
Go back to reason, Stilgar.
He's not The One.
我们有强大的朋友
We have powerful friends.
你们帮助我们离开这里 去卡拉丹 你们会得到很好的回报
You help us off world, to Caladan,
you will be well rewarded.
你能提供什么财富 比得上你身体里的水
What wealth can you offer
beyond the water in your flesh.
这个男孩还小 他可以学习我们的生活之道
The boy is young. He can learn our ways.
他可能获得庇护
He may have sanctuary.
但那个女人没有受过训练
But the woman isn't trained
太老了 学不会
and too old to learn.
退后 你们这些蠢货
Back, you dogs!
她会割断我的喉咙
She'll cut my throat.
你为何不说你是练过玄秘之道的女战士
Why didn't you say you were
a weirding woman and a fighter?
我们聊得不多
The conversation ran short.
冷静 女人 冷静
Peace, woman, peace.
我走眼了
I misjudged.
太阳升起来了 我们必须赶往泰布穴地
The sun is rising.
We must reach Sietch Tabr.
这些陌生人的命运将在那里决定
The fate of the strangers
will be decided there.
在那之前 他们都受我庇护
Until then, they are under my protection.
我向你保证
I give you my word.
我不会让你伤害我的朋友
I would not have let you
hurt my friends.
他们说你是马赫迪
They say you are the Mahdi.
但你看起来像个小男孩
But you look like a little boy.
你选择了最艰难的上山之道 我会告诉你更简单的
You chose the hardest way up. Follow me.
出发 出发
Take off! Take off!
把它给我
Give it to me.
当你配得上 你会拥有属于自己的毛拉手枪
You would have your own maula pistol
when you've earned it.
把它给我
Give it to me.
契妮 你负责新来的人 确保他们在旅途中平安无事
Chani, take charge of the newcomers.
See that they are safe in the journey.
我们走
Let's go.
我不带他们
I will not have them.
詹米 我已经说过了 别胡来
Jamis, I have spoken. Be still.
你说话像个领袖 但只有最强大的人才是领袖
You talk like a leader,
but the strongest leads.
她击败了你
She bested you.
我要提出艾姆泰尔法则
I invoke the Amtal.
- 你不能挑战萨亚迪娜女祭司 - 那谁会以她之名战斗
-You may not challenge a sayyadina.
-Then who will fight in her name?
詹米 别这样 别这样 黑夜快过去
Jamis, don't do this. Don't.
The night is fading.
那就让太阳来见证死亡吧
Then the sun will witness this death.
她的捍卫者在哪
Where is her champion?
我接受她的捍卫者
I accept her champion.
保罗·厄崔迪必须死
Paul Atreides must die…
为了魁萨茨·哈德拉克的崛起
for Kwisatz Haderach to rise.
不要害怕 不要反抗
Don't be frightened. Don't resist.
遇人杀人 遇神杀神
When you take a life, you take your own.
我不相信你们是利桑·阿尔·盖布
I don't believe you are the Lisan al-Gaib.
但我希望你死得光荣
But I want you to die with honor.
这把晶牙匕是我姑奶奶送给我的
This crysknife was given to me
by my great-aunt.
它是用大沙虫夏胡鲁的一颗牙齿做成的
It's made from a tooth of Shai-Hulud,
the great sand worm.
如果你拿着它死去 将是一个巨大的荣誉
This would be a great honor
if you to die holding it.
异星人在哪里
Where is the outworlder?
詹米是个好战士 他不会让你受折磨的
Jamis is a good fighter.
He won't let you suffer.
契妮
Chani…
没关系
Never mind.
愿你刀断人亡
May your knife chip and shatter.
你应该感谢我的剑
You should welcome my blade.
世道艰难 人必有一死
This world will kill you.
此路最快
Quicker this way.
还不投降
Do you yield?
这孩子不知道我们的规矩
The boy does not know our rule.
艾姆泰尔法则没有投降 只有死亡
There is no yielding under the Amtal
rule, only death is the test of that.
- 他在玩弄他么  - 没有
-Is he toying with him?
-No.
保罗从没杀过人
Paul has never killed a man.
魁萨茨·哈德拉克
Kwisatz Haderach.
站起来 觉醒吧
Climb up. Rise.
你现在是我们的一员了 一命换一命
You're one of us now. A life for a life.
- 跟我们一起去泰布穴地 - 不
-Come with us to Sietch Tabr.
-No.
保罗需要离开这里
Paul needs to get off world.
你们一定有门道 你们有走私贩 有飞船
You must have ways.
You have smugglers, you have ships.
- 没有 - 你们有
-No.
-You have--
是皇帝派我们来的
The Emperor sent us to this place.
我父亲来到这里
And my father came…
不是为了香料 不是为了财富
Not for spice, not for the riches,
而是为了你们的力量
but for the strength of your people.
我的人生之路将走向沙漠
My road leads into the desert.
我能看见
I could see it.
只要你们愿意接受我们 我们就跟你们走
If you'll have us, we will come.
沙漠力量
Desert power.
这只是开始
This is only the beginning.